<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ivan Pribec</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ivan Pribec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 — Ivan Pribec — All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the closed form coefficients of Laguerre polynomials</title>
      <link>/posts/2021/12/evaluating-the-closed-form-coefficients-of-laguerre-polynomials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021/12/evaluating-the-closed-form-coefficients-of-laguerre-polynomials/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating the closed form coefficients of Laguerre polynomials For some numerical applications it can be useful to work with the closed form expression for Laguerre polynomials. The closed form is given by
 $$L_n(x) = \sum_{k=0}^n {n \choose k} \frac{(-1)^k}{k!} x^k$$ (1)  We can evaluate the coefficients with the help of the factorial formula
 $$\binom{n}{k} = \frac{n!}{k!\,(n-k)!}$$ (2)  Since $n$ and $k$ are both integers, the coefficients are rational numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a personal website using Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/2020/02/setting-up-a-personal-website-using-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020/02/setting-up-a-personal-website-using-hugo/</guid>
      <description>As many before me, I&#39;ve decided I need a website to share some of my work and ideas in an uncensored fashion. I set up this page almost a year ago, but I didn&#39;t add any content in the meanwhile. This was in part simply due to lack of motivation and second due to focusing on other projects (I&#39;m saving some of these for blog posts).
Getting back to the website was easier this time round.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is the world’s fastest framework for building websites. It is written in Go.
It makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 https://github.com/russross/blackfriday https://github.com/alecthomas/chroma https://github.com/muesli/smartcrop https://github.com/spf13/cobra https://github.com/spf13/viper  Learn more and contribute on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code development</title>
      <link>/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code/</guid>
      <description>In my free time I like to work on scientific coding projects in Fortran.
Fortran interfaces Fortran 2003 added features for interoperability with the C programming language. These can be accesed through the intrinsic iso_c_binding module and allow smooth interfacing between the two languages for a certain set of interoperable types. This way Fortran programmers can gain access to the numerous libraries written in C/C++ and vice versa.
Using the C-Fortran interoperability I have written Fortran interfaces for the following (scientific) software libraries:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m doing now</title>
      <link>/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/now/</guid>
      <description>This is my /now page, inspired by Derek Sivers and others at nownownow.com.
 (Last updated on 17/02/2019.)
At university I’m currently working on a project report on pasta drying, analyzing CT datasets of dry pasta, and writing a scientific publication on the same topic. Sounds dry, but it’s not, really. ;)
Outside of work I’m currently:
 Creating my personal website. Adding finishing touches to the Modern Fortran NLopt wrapper.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
